菜单上有什么?
What's on the menu?
有可能是咸鱼
It could be ceviche
臭臭的  那是彭彭
Stinky-oo, it's Pumbaa
丁满  我跟你说
I got to tell you, Timon...
这首歌真是让我感动极了
that song always gets me right here.
是啊  彭彭
Yeah, Pumbaa.
好啦  够了
Well, enough of that.
丁满  你在干嘛
Timon, what are you doing?
我快转到我们出现的地方啊
I'm fast forwarding to the part where we come in.
可是你不能这样做
But you can't go out of order.
才怪  我的猪朋友
Au contraire, my porcine pal.
遥控器在我手上
I've got the remote.
但是这样大家会搞混了
But everyone's going to get confused.
我们得从故事一开始看起
We got to go back to the beginning of the story.
故事一开始没有我们啊
We're not in the beginning of the story.
有  我们一直都在
Yes, we were... the whole time.
是啊  可是观众不知道啊
Yeah, but they don't know that.
那何不告诉大家我们的故事
Then why don't we tell them our story?
嘿  我有个点子
Hey, l've got an idea.
告诉大家我们的故事吧
Why don't we tell them our story?
我喜欢那个点子
I like the sound of that.
就像是带着观众
A little backstage tour.
到后台参观
Take them behind the scenes for a revealing and intimate look...
在幕后观赏戏中戏一样
at the story within the story.
因为观众不知道  我们怎么会  在那里
Because what they don't know is how we really were there...
但我们一直都在那里
even though they didn't know we were there, you know?
说得太好了
Couldn't have said it better myself.
那么  我们要从头看起了?
So, does this mean we're going back to the beginning?
不  彭彭  不是
Oh, no, Pumbaa, no.
我们要从故事开始...
We're going way back...
的更早之前说起
to before the beginning.
《狮子王3：丁满彭彭历险记》
荣耀石
Pride Rock.
如此雄伟
So maestic.
真威武
So powerful.
真...  奇怪的名字
So bizarrely named.
岩石怎么会荣耀  只是块石头啊
Pumbaa, how can a rock be proud? It's a rock.
我猜是因为狮子是万兽之王吧
I think it's because a pride is what they call a group of lions.
是啊  狮子得到荣耀石
Oh, sure, the lions get Pride ock.
那我们这些狐獴呢
And what about us meerkats?
我所生长的地方  没啥值得一提的
Where I come from, we didn't have nothing to be proud of.
那啥...
Why...
当我还是只小狐獴
When I was a young meerkat
当他还是只小狐獴
When he was a young meerkat
非常好
Very nice.
谢谢
Thanks.
也许带他们
But maybe it would be safer...
看看我的故乡比较好
if I just show them where I came from.
真的吗  我们能看看你成长的地方?
Oh, boy! Do we get to see where you grew up?
是啊  只是不太雅观
Yeah, Pumbaa, but it ain't pretty.
请坐下  还没有拍完呢
Please remain seated while the camera is in motion.
我们到啦
Here we are.
从荣耀石到这个令人羞愧的窝
From Pride rock to the pity of shame.
我们在食物链的很下层  我们生活在地底下
We're so slow on the food chain, we're underground.
你们可以不相信我
But you don't have to take my word for it.
但听听我的狐獴同胞们怎么说
I'll ust let my fellow meerkats do the talking.
那是什么  那是什么
What was that, what was what?
What was that, what was that?
哪里  什么  在哪里  那是什么
Where, what, where, where, What was that?
嘘...
Shh!
快呀  土狼要来啦
Quick, before the hyena come
安全啦
Clear.
挖个地道  挖呀挖  挖个地道  挖呀挖
Digga tunnah, dig, digga tunnah
等你完成  就有一个大地道
When you're done, you dig a bigger tunnah
挖个地道  挖呀挖  挖个地道  挖呀挖
Digga tunnah, dig, digga tunnah
快  在土狼来之前
Quick, before the hyena come
挖个地道  挖呀挖  挖个地道  挖呀挖
Dig, digga tunnah, dig, digga tunnah
不停地挖呀  永远也挖不完
You could dig and never get done
挖个地道  挖呀挖  挖个地道  挖呀挖
Digga tunnah, dig, digga tunnah
那是什么
What was that?
快  在土狼来之前
Quick before the hyena come, dig
挖地道是我们的工作
Digga tunnah is what we do
生命就像是地道  等待我们挖掘
Life's a tunnah we're diggin' through
挖地道为我们所歌颂
Digga tunnah is what we sing
挖地道就是我们的一切
Digga tunnah is everything
泥和土是狐獴的朋友
Mud and clay is a meerkat's friend
布满于每个角落
Always more around every bend
无止无尽的泥和土
And when you get to your tunnah's end
哈利路亚  继续挖呀
Hallelujah, let's dig again, dig
挖个地道  挖呀挖  挖个地道  挖呀挖
Digga tunnah, dig, digga tunnah
等你完成  就有一个大地道
When it's done, you dig a bigger tunnah
挖个地道  挖呀挖  挖个地道  挖呀挖
Digga tunnah, dig, digga tunnah
那是什么
What was that?
快  在土狼来之前
Quick, before the hyena come
挖呀
Dig
丁满  对不起
Timon! Excuse me.
有没有看到我儿子?  他有没有经过这里?
Have you seen my son? Has he been through here?
丁满
Timon!
挖地道啊...
Dig, digga tunnah
麦斯叔叔?
Uncle Max?
别紧张  你看到丁满没?
Uncle Max, relax. Have you seen Timon?
我没看到  今天还真不赖
No, I haven't, and what a day it's been.
没有骨折  没有擦伤
No fractures, no lacerations...
没有脑震荡  没有挫伤  或任何形式种类的伤
no concussions, contusions, or injuries of any sort.
事实上
As a matter of fact...
这里没有任何丁满工作过的迹象
there's no sign of Timon's handiwork anywhere.
那应该是...
That would be...
丁满
Timon!
嗨  大家好
Hey, everybody.
好样的  丁满
Nice work, Timon.
-干得好啊  闯祸大王  -除了他  谁会开天窗?
- Way to go, tunnel klutz. - Who else could break a hole?
一星期四次  又创记录了
Four in one week... a new record.
怎么搞的
Not again.
什么  这叫天窗
What? It's called a skylight.
很有创意吧
Wow. lsn't that creative?
天窗
A skylight.
我会跟他谈谈的
I'll just have a word with him.
我只想为我们可悲的生活
I was just trying to shed a little light...
增添一点光彩
on our pathetic existence.
丁满  不能再乱来了
Timon, this can't go on.
这个月你已捅破了四面墙
Just this month, you've pulled down four walls...
搞塌了两个出口
and collapsed two tunnel exits.
我们应该互相照顾
We have to look after each other.
只有这样才能生存
Our survival depends on it.
有什么用呢  我们就知道挖
What's the point? All we do is dig...
挖了后藏起来  藏起后再挖
so we can hide, and hide so we can dig.
我想到不用挖洞的地方去生活
I want to be where we don't have to dig tunnels...
能在地面上抬头挺胸生活
and live with our heads stuck in the sand.
梦想有个更好的家有什么错
What's so bad about dreaming of a better home?
我要给你看样东西
I want to show you something.
丁满  你看
Look, Timon.
来呀  看
Go on, look.
看看远方的地平线
Look out to the horizon...
穿过那片树林
past the trees...
通过那片草地
over the grasslands.
阳光所照到的地方...
Everything the light touches...
都有主人
belongs to someone else.
我以为你要说点别的
Funny. I thought you were going a whole different direction with this.
我能说什么  是大自然的安排
What can I say? It's nature's design.
我们就是其他动物的食物
She's right. We're food for other animals...
一顿移动的美食
a moveable feast...
所有的动物都可以享用
feared by no one and eaten by all.
可是他们死后会变成草
But when they die, they become the grass...
我们吃草  对吧
and we eat the grass, right?
不对  我们吃草不消化
Not exactly. We can't digest grass.
我们无法忍受草
We're grass intolerant.
行啦  麦斯  谢谢
OK, Max. Thank you.
你帮了大忙了
You've been a big help.
狐獴  是别人的晚餐
Meerkat... it's what's for dinner.
谢谢你  麦斯叔叔
Thank you, Uncle Max.
我想麦斯叔叔的头  一定多撞了一块石头
I think uncle Max dislodged one too many rocks with his skull.
但他说的没错  丁满
But he's right, Timon.
噢  我知道这里  一定有你可以胜任的活
Oh, I just know there's a way for you to fit in here.
好吧  今天谁放哨?
All right, who's on sentry duty?
对啦
That's it.
我的儿子放哨
That's it... my son on sentry duty.
"哨兵丁满"
Timon the sentry.
丁满当哨兵?
Timon the sentry?
不用土狼来  现在就杀了我吧
Why don't you save the hyenas the trouble and kill me now?
现在就杀了我
Just kill me now.
他说的有道理
He has a point.
你只要监视那些土狼就行啦  看到他们来了你就喊
All you have to do is watch for hyenas and yell if you see one.
看看小乔
Look at Iron Joe.
不要闭上眼睛  不要到处乱看
Don't close your eyes! Don't look away!
我们需要有人放哨
Somebody's got to guard us!
我们需要有人保护
Somebody's gotta protect us!
嗯  我被你说服啦
Well, now l'm convinced.
这是
Listen, it's outside...
在微风里  在外面的天空下
up in the breeze, under the wide open sky.
这不正是你想要的吗
Isn't that what you want?
难道你还想...
Or maybe you would rather have him...
让他继续挖洞吗
go back on the digging crew.
不
No!
好  就这样决定了
Good, then we all agree.
丁满  要听麦斯叔叔的话
Timon, listen to Uncle Max.
他会教你一切的
He'll teach you everything you need to know.
宝贝  这次要好好干啊
And, honey, try to make this one work.
跑来闻去  缩头藏尾
Scurry, sniff, flinch!
好啦
Good. Now...
看到土狼来了  你该做什么?
what do we do if we see a hyena?
喊"妈咪"?
Scream, ''Mommy''?
对啦  先生
That's right, mister...
因为这个世界到处都是危险
because the world out there is fraught with danger.
我告诉你  到处都是
Fraught, I tell you!
啊  孩子  到处都有敌人
Oh, boy. It's the fraught fest.
...等着把我们撕成碎片
...rip us limb from limb.
好极了  麦斯叔叔
Bravo, Uncle Max.
拍成电影上映一定卖座
Way to sell it to the cheap seats.
尽管鼓掌吧
Applaud now, sonny boy...
等到没手时看你怎么鼓
but try clapping when you don't have any hands.
跑来闻去  缩头藏尾
Scurry, sniff, flinch.
听起来还不错
I like the sound of that.
跑来闻去  缩头藏尾
Scurry, sniff, flinch.
生活不该只是惊慌失措
There's more to life than panic
担心成为他人的美食
And bein' some other guy's snack, yuck
我也许是很好吃的健康食品
I may be delicious organic
可是我这道小菜要反抗了
But this little entree's fighting back
我再也不挖洞了
I'm gonna put digging tunnels behind me
我要开始新的生活
And live at a new altitude
我要去摘星星  为的是提醒我
I'm gonna reach for the stars to remind me
狐獴不是他人的食品
That meerkats are not merely food
从现在开始
For once l'll be
我要照顾自己
Lookin' out for me
我告诉你
Yeah, l'll tell you what I want
这只狐獴要走了
This cat is movin' on
因为他的生活  一点都不美好
He's a bon vivant who's missin' out on bon
我要成为大亨  远离这片沙漠
I'd be a bigger cheese far from the desert scene
一阵凉爽的清风  一片怡人的绿地
A little cooling breeze, a little patch of green
我要得意自在地
And l'll be snoozing in my hammock
躺在涓涓小溪边的吊床上
By a rippling stream
远离那些洞穴  远离那些挖洞的同伴
Many miles from any tunnel and the digging team
我要过好日子  这就是我的信仰
Looking after number one will be my only creed
这就是我所需要的
That's all I need
以前我总是逃来逃去
I've always been good at running away
现在我要主宰一切
Well, now I'm gonna run the show
以前我总被人视为盘中飧
I've always been seen as the ultimate prey
现在我的地位不同以往啦
But now my status ain't so quo
一个伟大的梦想
A dream sublime
那土狼...
It's hyena time...
看  一场晚餐秀
Oh, look, it's dinner and a show.
以前我以为  只有豆芽菜跟音乐搭得上边
And I thought beans were the only musical food.
喂  你也好啊
Well, hi to you, too.
丁满  现在不是玩的时候
This is no time for horseplay, Timon.
你应该在上面监视...
You're supposed to be up there looking out for...
土狼
hyenas!
瞧  他们四面奔逃
Whoa, look at them scramble.
我就喜欢看他们这个样子
And that's just how I like them...
一片混乱
scrambled...
还到处窜来窜去
and a little bit runny.
土狼
Hyenas!
进来
Get in here.
你怎么啦  疯啦
What are you, a meshugginah?
跑来闻去?  缩头藏尾?
Stumpy? Flinchy? Swifty?
总算万幸
Oh, what a relief.
大家都...
Everybody's...
麦斯叔叔在哪里
Where's Uncle Max?
快逃命啊
Max! Run for your life!
快装死
Play dead!
你就快到了
Almost there!
今秋麂皮最时髦...
Suede is the look for this fall.
怎么啦
Hey, what's going on?
彭彭  你坐在遥控器上啦
Pumbaa, you're sitting on the remote.
什么  对不起  我以为是块饼干
Huh? Oh, sorry. I thought it was a brownie.
麦斯  你成功了
You've got it, Max!
麦斯
Max!
我在该跑的时候  竟然缩头藏尾
I flinched when I should've scurried.
总是很有趣  是吧
Oh, man. lt just never gets old, does it?
这游戏总是玩不腻
The classics never do, honey.
我想我应该向大家道歉
I guess I owe everyone an apology.
好吧  我犯了个小小的错误
All right, so I made a teensy mistake.
你们在放哨的时候  肯定也唱过歌
Like we all haven't broken into song on sentry duty before.
唱过的  举手我看看
Come on. Let me have a show of hands.
好吧
OK.
也许还需要段时间
Maybe it's a little too soon...
以后谈到此事我们会开怀大笑
but l'm sure we're all going to laugh about this someday.
相信我
Trust me.
我相信过你
I did trust you.
可是...
But...
宝贝儿...
Aw, sweetie...
我永远也不适合这里
I'm never going to fit in here.
没有人喜欢我
Nobody even likes me.
大家都喜欢你  宝贝儿
Sure they do, honey. Sure they do.
妈妈  只有你喜欢我
Besides you, Ma.
除了我以外...还有...
Besides me? There's...
我要去找属于我的地方  这里不适合我
I have to find my place, but it isn't here.
这里适合你  我们只是还没有发现
Yes, it is. We just haven't found it yet.
我们一定会发现的
But we will.
我有个主意  你可以...
Here's an idea. You can...
别再弄头发了  妈妈  适合我的地方在外面
Stop with the hair already. My place is out there, Ma.
我不知道那里有多远  可是我一定要去
I may not know exactly where or how far, but I got to go.
不  等等  如果我们...
No, wait, wait. I know. lf we just...
妈妈
Ma.
宝贝儿  我希望你能找到  属于你的地方
Well, I hope you find what you're looking for, honey.
我爱你
I love you.
我爱你  妈妈
I love you, Ma.
丁满
Oh, Timmy.
我的小丁满
My Timmy.
妈妈
Mom...
快憋死我啦
choking. Not breathing.
难怪大家会觉得我很古怪
And people wonder why I have issues.
我不会有事的
Oh, l'll be OK.
我知道
Oh, I know you will. You will.
多加小心
Be careful!
我会的
I will.
别跟陌生人讲话
Don't talk to strangers!
知道了  妈妈
I know, Ma!
耳朵后面别忘了洗干净
Remember, wash behind your ears!
妈妈  我不是小孩儿了
Ma, l'm not a kid anymore!
不要独自去游泳
Never go swimming without a buddy!
知道了
Got it.
什么?
What?
What?!
再见  妈妈
Good-bye, Ma.
就这样  情绪高昂
And so, with high spirits...
我勇敢地出发了
I boldly ventured off...
到狐獴从不敢去的地方
where no meerkat had dared to go before.
把过去抛在脑后
I put my past behind me...
决不回头
and never looked back.
妈咪
Mommy! Mommy!
我在干什么
What am I doing?
我该朝哪个方向走
Which way should I go?
这要看你想到哪里去
That depends on what you think.
真方便
How convenient.
无所不知的猴子即时出现
Enter omniscient monkey, right on cue.
你知道人们怎么说的
Well, you know what they say.
学生准备好了  老师就会出现
When the student is ready, the teacher appears.
这下好了  你用不着幸运签饼了
That's it. No more fortune cookies for you.
你是从哪里来的
Hey, where'd you come from?
更好的问题是  你要到哪里去
Oh, the better question is, where are you going?
一个美好的地方  先生  那里...
Someplace wonderful, mister, where...
你没听到几分钟前
You didn't happen to catch the song...
我唱的那首歌吗
I sang a few minutes ago, did you?
我没能欣赏到
I didn't have the pleasure.
重复一下  我要到外面  一个美丽的地方去生活
To recap, I want to live in some beautiful place outside...
一个让我无忧无虑  不再躲藏和担忧的地方
a carefree place where I don't have to hide or worry.
一种无忧无虑的生活
Life without worry.
你是要找  "哈库拉马塔塔"
You seek hakuna matata.
哈库拉他个头?
Harpoon a tomato?
哈库拉马塔塔...
Hakuna Matata
是"无忧无虑"
it means ''No worries.''
太好啦  用你的棍子
Perfect. Mind taking that stick of yours...
给我画个地图好吗
and drawing me a map, bub?
嘿
Hey!
要想找到它  你必须超越你的视线
To find it, you must look beyond what you see.
这是什么意思
What the heck is that supposed to mean?
意思就是你要超越自己的视线
It means look beyond what you see.
超越我的视线?
Beyond what I see.
瞧这个猴子  跟我讲起哲学来啦
Get a load of the monkey getting all existential on me.
超越我的视线
Beyond what I see.
这音乐让我没法子思考了
It's kind of hard to think with all this music.
超越...
Beyond...
我的视线
what I see.
等等  我感觉到了
Wait a second. It's coming to me.
不是因为吃了鼻涕虫  就是我大彻大悟了
It's either that slug I ate or l'm having an epiphany.
我要到那块大石头那里去
I'm going to the big pointy rock!
对吧?
Right?
那只陌生猴子是谁啊
Who was that strange monkey?
好吧
Ah, well.
梦想之家  我来啦
Dream home, here I come.
你好?
Hello?
奇怪却很有智慧的猴子?
Strange but wise monkey?
你知道  第一印象很重要
You know, first impressions are very important.
我以为你是个滑稽演员
I thought you were a scream.
现在就吃了我吧  请你快点
Just eat me now... and please make it fast.
我对疼痛的忍耐有限
I got a low threshold for pain.
别紧张  小家伙  我不会吃你的
Easy, easy there, little guy. I'm not going to eat you.
什么  不吃?
What? You're not?
那你跟踪我干什么
Then why were you stalking me?
我看你走过
Well, gee, I saw you go by...
我觉得  你这个小家伙
and I figured a little fellow like you
不该独自出来
shouldn't be out here all alone.
那你呢  你不也是独自一人吗
Hey, what about you? You're all alone.
你是独自一人  是不是
You are all alone, aren't you?
是啊  大多数动物  都离我远远的
Yeah. Most animals give me a pretty wide berth.
是吗  连那些饿的也不吃你?
They do? Even the hungry ones?
是的  我让他们离我远远的
Yeah. I drive almost everyone away.
他们看到我来了就躲了起来
People see me coming, and they run for cover.
他们唯恐闪躲不及
They can't get out of the way fast enough.
真是这样啊
You don't say, you don't say.
一定是你发光的獠牙
Must be the gleam on those vicious tusks, huh?
把恐惧刺入了他们的心脏
Strikes fear into their hearts.
实际上  他们说  我倒他们的胃口
Actually, they say I wreck their appetite.
就像是你有这个...  特异功能
Wow. It's like you have this special power.
特异功能?
Special power?
非常特别的功能
Well, it's pretty powerful, all right.
太好了  我雇你了
Perfect. You're hired.
好  雇我干什么
Great! For what?
带我到那块大石头那儿
To get me to a little worry-free haven...
无忧无虑的地方去
out by that big pointy rock.
你要我跟你一起去?
And you want me to come with you?
我身边又没有其他  可爱的大疣猪
Do you see any other big lovable chunk of warthog here...
还刚好长着一双獠牙
who also happens to have razor-sharp tusks...
能驱赶那些野兽?
and the ability to repel predators?
我是你的猪
I'm your pig.
你和我  咱俩看法完全一致
You and me, I can tell... we see eye to eye.
你是说  像朋友一样?
You mean, like friends?
别心急  大个子
Whoa, easy there, big fella.
我是说像是...  熟人
I'd say more like... acquaintances.
好吧  总算是个开始
Well, it's a start.
握个手吧  熟人
Put 'er there, acquaintance.
-我是丁满  -彭彭
- l'm Timon. - Pumbaa.
不  不会吧
No, really.
那好
All right, then.
我们上路吧
Let's hit the road.
上路...
You got it...
熟人
acquaintance.
那么  跟我讲明一件事
So, clear up one thing for me.
如果你不吃我
If you weren't going to eat me...
你算是哪种古怪的野猪啊
what kind of a wacky, wild pig are you?
我是食虫者
I'm an insectivore.
吃虫子的
A bug eater.
我也是
Well, me, too.
以前不知道还有个专有名字
I just never had a name for it.
我喜欢吃爬虫
I'm kind of partial to the crawly critters myself.
-你呢  -我有时喜欢吃带翅膀的
-How about you, big boy? -l prefer the ones with wings.
彭彭  这可能是个  熟人关系的...
Pumbaa, this could be the start of a beautiful...
美好开端
acquaintanceship.
我们现在回到开头了
OK, so now we're back at the beginning.
对吧  丁满?
Right, Timon?
说对啦  朋友
Oh, you got that right, pally.
运气终于好起来啦
At last, things were looking up.
肩上有阳光  脚旁有风
I had the sun on my shoulders, the wind at my heels...
心中有首歌
A song in my heart.
还有一个大胖家伙保护着我
And to protect me, a great big fat guy.
你真的觉得我很胖?
You really think I look fat?
彭彭...
Pumbaa, Pumbaa, Pumbaa.
你是头猪  这是表扬你呢
You're a pig. It's a compliment.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
这是生命之轮
It's the circle of life
它环绕着我们
And it moves us all
那就是了...  那块大石头
There it is... the big pointy rock.
我们就快到了
Oh, baby, we're almost there.
我想我们来晚了
I think we're a little late.
这里人真多
It's a land rush.
那个大嘴的猴子
That loudmouth monkey.
一定是他告诉了全世界
He must've blabbed it to the whole world.
他到底说什么啦
What exactly did he say?
超越你的视线
Look beyond what you see.
也许你的视线该超越这块石头
So maybe you're supposed to look beyond the big pointy rock.
也许我该看看大石头的那边
Maybe l'm supposed to look beyond the big pointy rock.
我们来看看吧?
Well, let's have a little look, shall we?
超越我的视线
Beyond what I see.
好啊
What do you know?
那只猴子眼光独到  可以去搞房地产了
The monkey's got an eagle eye for real estate!
丁满  看
Timon, look!
是那只猴子
Hey! It's the monkey!
他举的是什么东西?
What's that he's holding up?
管它呢  不重要
Aw, who cares? It's not important.
来呀  我的梦中家园在等着我
Come on! My dream home awaits.
我不喜欢很多人在一起
I don't do so well in crowds.
我们绕着过去吧
Maybe we better go around.
你不知道
Don't you know the shortest distance...
我和我的梦中家园最短的距离
between me and my dream home...
是一条直线?  跟我来
is a straight line? Follow me!
对不起
Excuse me.
天啊
Goodness.
让一让  让一让
Make room, make room!
小心点  长角的
Watch it, twiggy.
我要过去
I'm walkin' here!
丁满  我有话跟你说
Timon! There's something I gotta tell you.
彭彭...
Pumbaa, Pumbaa, Pumbaa.
等我们安排妥当后  自然有足够时间聊天
We'll have plenty of time to chat once we settle in.
我真的想休息一下
I could really use a rest stop.
别急  你有机会休息的
Don't worry. You'll get your second wind.
我有点不舒服
I got a really bad feeling!
会好的
It'll pass!
相信我  会好的
Trust me. lt'll pass.
看  犀牛在鞠躬呢
Oh, look, the rhinos are bowing.
我们最好也鞠躬
We'd better bow, too.
瞧  陛下  大家都向王子跪拜表达敬意呢
Look, sire, how they kneel before the royal son.
这就是你的特异功能?
So, I guess that's your special power, huh?
真猛啊
What a weapon!
你是说  你不在意?
You mean, you don't mind?
你开玩笑?
Are you kidding?
只是放屁嘛
It was a gas!
我不喜欢炫耀自己
Well, I don't like to toot my own horn.
这样最好
Yeah, that's probably for the best.
彭彭  我们走
Let's go, Pumbaa!
你来带路吧
Lead the way!
这就对了  朋友
This is it, buddy boy.
家  温馨的家
Home, sweet home.
我不想和任何人分享
And I don't gotta share it with anybody. Ha ha!
你不感到孤独吗
Don't you get, you know, lonely out here?
孤独?  我会感到无忧无虑
Lonely? Try commitment-free.
挤来挤去的  让我感觉
The elbow-to-elbow life reminds me...
回到了以前的家
a little too much of home.
这地方什么都有
This place has everything...
清爽的饮料  舒适的小吊床
cool refreshments, cozy little hammock...
可爱的水流  这些全都属于我
a lovely water feature, and it's all mine.
你的梦想实现了  丁满...
Well, it's really coming together, Timon, so...
我想我该走了
so, I guess I'll just be going.
等等
Wait a minute, now. Wait.
没有规定说你一定要走
There's no law that says you have to go.
我是说  如果你想...
I mean, if you want...
太好了  我已经铺好了两张床
Great! I already made up two beds!
一张是你的  一张是我的
One for you, and one for me.
这些整理工作把我累坏了
Gee, all this construction work has me bushed.
我要早睡了
Think l'll turn in early.
晚安
Good night!
睡个好觉
Sleep tight.
祝今晚梦见臭虫
Dream of bedbugs tonight.
家  温馨的家
Home, sweet home indeed.
嘿  小声一点
Hey, keep it down up there!
我们有邻居吗  我们该去打个招呼才对
We have neighbors? We should go say hello.
吵闹的邻居
Noisy neighbors.
这下房子不值钱了
There go the property values.
地上走的  天上飞的  大家都来听啊
Let's hear it in the herd and on the wing
这将是国王辛巴的一件美事
It's gonna be King Simba's finest fling
我真等不及想当国王了
Oh, I just can't wait to be king
好啊  我们到了戏剧街
Perfect. We moved to the theater district.
瞧瞧这帮家伙
Get a load of these guys.
闭嘴啦
Knock it off!
等不及想...
Just can't wait
当心
Timon, look out!
当国王
To be king
我没事
I'm OK.
艺人
Show people.
打起精神  彭彭
Chin up, Pumbaa.
我们的梦中家园就在附近
Our dream home's around here somewhere.
我到过一个地方
You know, Timon, I once came across a place...
那可能就是你要找的地方
that might be just what you're looking for.
壮观的瀑布
Spectacular waterfalls...
在一个沙漠绿洲里
set in a lush tropical oasis...
一排排...
a scrumptious array of...
算啦
Hey, hey. Forget it, Pumbaa.
我是现实主义者  不喜欢追逐幻想
I'm a realist, and l'm not gonna go chasing after some fantasy.
我要超越我的视线
I'm going beyond what I see.
如果你总是超越视线
But if you always go beyond what you see...
你怎么知道你到了呢?
how do you know when you're there?
我告诉你我知道
Oh, l'll tell you how I know.
我们到啦
We're there!
这块地方不错
This is a lovely spot.
乡村式的独特风景
Lovely, rustic, picturesque.
家  温馨的家  彭彭
Home sweet home, Pumbaa.
家  温馨的...
Home sweet ho...
需要修整一下
I mean, sure, it needs a little work...
但结构还不错
but it's got good bones.
这是大象墓园
After all, this is an elephant graveyard...
谁会到大象墓园来呢
and who would ever come to an elephant graveyard?
陛下  土狼在追孩子们
Sire, the hyenas are after the children!
我看到食肉动物了
I see carnivores.
超越你的视线
Beyond what you see.
Beyond what you see!
如果我现在跟你提
Timon? Would this be a bad time...
我去过的那地方你会介意吗?
to bring up that little place I told you about?
这就是家  温馨的家  宝贝
Hey! This is home sweet home, baby!
家...
Home...
蒸气  蒸气好
Steam! Steam is good.
蒸气是...  水
Steam is water. Gotta have water.
梦想之家就应该有水
You know, for the dream home.
蒸气的家  梦想之家
Steam home, dream home.
蒸气  蒸气  蒸气
Steam, steam, steam.
我在这里很幸福
I am perfectly happy right here!
这里很偏僻  隐蔽
It's remote, private...
没有不速之客
no unexpected visitors.
我觉得这不是
Somethin' tells me this ain't...
爱尔兰大河之舞
the traveling company of ''Riverdance.''
超越你的视线
Beyond what you see.
超越你的...
Beyond what you...
这样我怎么超越我的视线  看个屁啊?
Hey, how am I supposed to look beyond what I see beyond that?
对不起
Oh, sorry.
这地方缺少水和遮蔽物
What this place lacks in water and shade...
可是却有酷热和烈日
it makes up for with searing heat and blinding sunshine.
家  甜蜜家园  彭彭
Home sweet home, Pumbaa.
我们逃命吧?
Shall we run for our lives?
当然  快跑吧
Oh, yes, let's.
坚持住  丁满
Hang on, Timon!
这就对啦
This is it!
再见  残酷的世界
Good-bye, cruel world!
就这样?
That's it?
还不算太差嘛
That wasn't so bad.
丁满不会那么容易被打垮的
You can't knock old Timon down that easy!
来  出招吧
Yeah! Bring it on!
彭彭?
Pumbaa?
有个问题
Question...
我们有没有可能  从地球边上掉下去
is it possible to fall off the edge of the earth?
从技术上讲不会
Technically, no.
因为地球是圆的
The earth is round like a sphere, Timon...
没有边
so it doesn't actually have an edge.
我可以暂停一下吗?
You mind if I pause it for a second?
好啊  随你便
Sure, go ahead.
马上回来
Be right back.
这个世界真是小
It's a small world after all
这是个小小的世界
It's a small, small world
大家一起唱
Everybody
这个世界真是小
It's a small world after all
我买了大盒的  我们可以分享
OK, I got the jumbo so we could share.
你刚才在挖鼻孔吗
Were you just picking your nose?
没有  是里面有点痒
No, I had an itch on the inside.
丁满  你没事吧
Timon, you OK?
我放弃
I give up.
你不能放弃
But you can't give up.
我们还没找到梦想之家呢
We still haven't found our dream home.
算了吧  彭彭
Forget it, Pumbaa.
我拖着你乱跑已经够久了
I've been dragging you down long enough.
我要回家  我建议你也回家
I'm going home, and I suggest you do the same.
能回家我早就回了
I would if I could, but I can't.
你当然可以回家  朋友  我不会阻拦你的
Sure you can, buddy. I won't stop you.
我是说...
No, I mean...
我没有家
I don't have a home.
你没有家?  怎么啦?  你迷路啦?
You don't? What happened? Are you lost?
没有你喜欢的地方?
No place good enough for you?
你孤零零的  活在这个空荡荡的世界上?
What, you're all alone in this big empty world?
其实...
The truth is...
我也是孤独一人
I'm all alone, too.
彭彭  你是我唯一的朋友
Pumbaa, you're the only friend I've ever had.
你是说...
You mean...
是的  彭彭  而朋友要永远在一起
Yeah, Pumbaa... and friends stick together to the end.
丁满  你哭啦?
Timon, are you crying?
没有啦
I'm fine.
我只是眼里进了东西
I just have something in my eye.
来  擤一下
Here, blow.
拿去  彭彭
Here, Pumbaa.
真多谢啊
Gee, thanks.
好  我好多了
OK, l'm better.
可惜
Aw, well.
我们没有找到  那个完美的地方
It's too bad we never found that perfect place.
我们为何要听笨猴子的话
Why'd we ever listen to that stupid monkey?
我觉得你太早放弃了
I think maybe you're giving up too soon, Timon.
超越你的视线
Beyond what you see.
还记得我跟你提到的那个地方吗
Remember that place I told you about?
别提你那个地方了
Forget about your place.
看看我找到的地方
Get a load of what I found.
说到"超越我的视线"
Talk about beyond what you see.
这就是我们的梦想之家
Pumbaa, this is our dream home.
生动的景色
Dramatic views.
自己的吊床
Your very own porch swing.
水疗和三温暖
Hot tub and spa.
取之不尽的食物
Well stocked cupboard.
让我们庆祝一下
Let's celebrate!
那个猴子是对的
The monkey was right.
我们找到了...  完美的生活
We found it... the perfect life.
我去搞点吃的
I'll just whip up a little something.
他起的名字也最完美
He had the perfect name for it, too.
来吃吧
Come and get it.
非常漂亮的词语  还有独特的韵律
Such a wonderful phrase. It had this rhythm.
[节拍]
Laduda.
尝尝这个...  热鲔鱼蛋饼
Try this... hot tuna frittata.
不  不是
No, that's not it.
菠菜阿玛达
The spinach armada.
安静  我在想呢
Quiet, Pumbaa. I'm trying to think.
一勺干酪
A spoon of ricotta.
-两个字  -一份牛肉片
-Two words. -A wormy piccata.
-有六个音节  -行家的克喇塔
-Si syllables. -Kahuna colada.
-十二个字母  -蓝色的安奇拉塔
-Twelve letters. -A blue enchilada.
押韵
Rhymes with...
豆子一盘
Legumes on a platter.
这个可辣呀
This ought to be hotter.
-我忘了  -我要跳粘巴达
- I forget. - I got to lambada!
你还有心情跳舞?
Hey, how can you dance at a time like this?
我都快要想破头了
I'm dying here.
对不起  朋友
Sorry about that, pal.
哈库拉马塔塔
Hakuna Matata.
再说一遍?
Come again?
哈库拉马塔塔  就是无忧无虑
Hakuna matata... it means ''No worries.''
嘿  我有个主意
Hey, Timon, I got an idea.
我们来唱卡拉OK
Let's do a sing-along.
你开玩笑
Oh, you tease.
我喜欢卡拉OK  我来唱
I love karaoke. l'm there.
哈库拉马塔塔
Hakuna Matata
多么美妙的词语
What a wonderful phrase
哈库拉马塔塔
Hakuna Matata
不是一时流行的词语
Ain't no passin' craze
意思是无忧无虑
It means no worries
从今往后
For the rest of your days
等等
Wait a second.
彭彭  那虫子跑哪里去了
Pumbaa, where's the grub?
你是不是控制不住自己?
You just can't help yourself, can you?
对不起
Sorry.
这回要控制一点
OK, but this time, show a little self-control.
哈库拉马塔塔
Hakuna Matata
意思是无忧无虑
It means no worries
从今往后
For the rest of your days
没有任何烦恼的
It's our problem free
哲学
Philosophy
哈库拉马塔塔
Hakuna Matata
马塔塔  哈库拉马塔塔
Matata Hakuna Matata
Hahuna Ma...  什么啊?
Hahuna ma-what-a?
意思是无忧无虑
It means ''No worries.''
我明白了
I see.
于是  我就告诉那小子  去找哈库拉马塔塔
So, I told the boy to find hakuna matata...
你要超越自己的视线
you must look beyond what you see.
一个比喻
Oh, a metaphor.
实际上  那不是个...
Well, actually, it's not a meta...
你给丁满打比喻?
You used a metaphor on Timon?
他对什么都很认真
He takes things literally.
他在外边一定挨饿了
That's it. He's starving out there.
我知道
I just know it.
麦斯  丁满在外面找比喻
Max, Timon's out there chasing metaphors.
我得把他找回来
I've got to go find him.
你疯啦?
Are you nuts?
有家庭的支持真好  对吧
Nice to have a supportive family, isn't it?
好  我走啦
Well, here I go.
记住  千里之行
Remember, the journey of a thousand miles...
始于足下
begins with the first step.
谢谢  我这就迈出第一步
Thanks. Here's my first step.
看来拿豪猪打保龄球  不是什么好主意
This bowling for porcupines wasn't the best idea, huh?
是啊  这就跟拿屁股
Yeah. Got to be right up there...
钓鳄鱼一样糟糕
with bobbing for snapping turtles.
一定会留下疤痕的
That's going to leave a mark.
丁满  看  秃鹰
Hey, look, Timon, buzzards.
我们再来玩一轮  怎么样
What do you say, one more round?
行啊  我身上
Oh, sure. There must be some part of me...
一定还有没伤过的地方
we haven't injured yet.
拜托  拜托
Oh, please? Oh, please?
不  我累了
Nah, Pumbaa, l'm beat.
你玩吧  我要回去了
You go ahead. I'm calling it a day.
可是一个人玩没意思
But it's no fun alone.
有何不可
Aw, why not?
多玩一轮不会改变我们的命运
One more run won't change our lives.
谁知道那天命运是怎么把我们引到辛巴的面前的?
Who knows why fate led us to little Simba that day.
也许是因为我喜欢冒险
Maybe it was just my love of adventure...
或者是我内在的勇气
or my innate courage...
我大无畏的精神...
my valiant and fearless way of...
好了  是谁负责控制这些定格画面的
OK, who's in charge of the freeze frames?
对不起
Sorry.
不管怎么说...
Anywho...
营救辛巴不费吹灰之力
rescuing Simba was a cinch.
接下来才是可怕的部份
Then came the really scary part...
当父母
parenthood.
∮ 在丛林中，巨大的丛林 ∮
∮ In the jungle, the mighty jungle ∮
∮ 狮子今晚已经熟睡 ∮
∮ The lion sleeps tonight ∮
∮ 在丛林中，巨大的丛林 ∮
∮ In the jungle, the mighty jungle ∮
丁满  丁满
Timon. Timon.
丁满
Timon!
-我要去  -去?
- l got to go. - Go?
去哪里
Go where?
去...  尿尿啊
You know, go... bad.
你怎么不早说?  好  我们走
Oh, go? Why didn't you say so? Come on, let's go.
你该去时就得去啊
When you got to go, you got to go.
小狮子  下来
Young lion, get down from there.
好耶  从上面看起来你们像蚂蚁
All right! Man, you guys look like ants down there.
我数三下
I'm counting to three.
一  二
One, two...
三
three.
∮ 在丛林中，巨大的丛林 ∮
∮ In the jungle, the mighty jungle ∮
丁满
Timon.
又要去?
Again?
不  我渴了
No. l'm thirsty.
你知道这意味着
You know this means you'll be up again...
再过两个小时你又要去尿啦
about two hours from now.
∮ 丛林布吉乐 ∮
∮ Jungle boogie ∮
∮ 丛林布吉乐，兴奋起来 ∮
∮ Jungle boogie, get it on ∮
撑着点  辛巴  我来救你
Hang on, Simba! I'll save you!
丁满?
Timon?
∮ 巨大的丛林 ∮
∮ The mighty jungle... ∮
我们这样走下去会变老的
We're going to get old walking across this thing.
∮ 在丛林中，巨大的... ∮
∮ In the jungle, the might... ∮
丁满?
Timon?
你为什么就是不愿意
What have you got against the concept...
好好睡一觉呢
of a good night's sleep, huh?
其实  我...
Actually, l...
我做了个噩梦
I had a bad dream.
啊  这样啊...
Oh, well...
不是我
It wasn't me.
小子做了个噩梦
Junior had a bad dream.
你过来和我们一起来睡吧?
Why don't you sleep over here with us?
我的彭彭  就是你的彭彭
Mi Pumbaa, su Pumbaa.
好耶
All right!
∮ 狮子今晚已经熟睡 ∮
∮ The lion sleeps tonight ∮
晚安
Good night.
好好睡
Sleep tight.
祝你今晚梦见臭虫...
Dream of bedbugs tonight.
∮ 我的小亲亲 ∮
∮ My little darling ∮
∮ 不要害怕，我的小亲亲 ∮
∮ Don't fear, my little darling ∮
∮ 嘿哈，我的小亲亲 ∮
∮ Hey-a, oh, my little darling ∮
∮ 不要害怕，我的小亲亲 ∮
∮ Oh, don't fear, my little darling ∮
∮ Don't fear, my little darling ∮
∮ 嘿哈，我的小亲亲 ∮
∮ Hey-a, oh, my little darling ∮
你早上起床打哈欠的时候
Watch where you aim that morning breath.
提醒我们躲开你张嘴的方向
That should come with a warning label.
这真的会臭醒人
Whoo, what a wake-up call.
看来有人有起床气喔
Looks like someone woke up on the wrong side of the warthog.
怎么啦  老爹
What's the matter, pops?
哈库拉马塔塔  没用啦?
Had a little too much hakuna matata?
小子  哈库拉马塔塔  是我发明的
Sonny boy, I invented hakuna matata.
是吗  那是我改良了它
Oh, yeah? Well, I perfected it.
当然罗
Sure you did, sure you did.
彭彭  谁保持吃虫子后  打饱嗝最长的记录
Pumbaa, who holds the record for the world's longest bug belch?
那应该是辛巴
That would be Simba.
好
All righty, then.
谁是吃鼻涕虫的冠军
Who's the champion at slug swallowing?
还是辛巴
Simba again.
-嚼蟋蟀呢  -辛巴
- Cricket crunching? - Simba.
-吞虫虫呢  -辛巴
- Grub gulping? -Simba.
-吃蛆呢  -还是辛巴
- Maggot munching? - Still Simba.
吃蜗牛呢
Snail slurping?
没人是冠军  我们还没比过
Nobody. We never had a snail eating contest before.
我觉得这不是什么好主意
I don't think this is such a good idea.
我早说过这不是个好主意
I told you this wasn't such a good idea.
这比赛证明了青出于蓝
Thus did the pupil surpass the teacher.
你又跟那猴子一起混啦
You've been hanging around with the monkey again, haven't you?
我们的辛巴长大啦
Our Simba is growing up.
这就是我以前  抱过的那个小家伙?
ls this the little boy I carried?
什么时候他长得这么高了
When did he grow to be so tall?
那好像还是昨天的事
Wasn't it yesterday
他还是小小的?
When he was small?
日出  日落
Sunrise, sunset
时光匆匆飞逝
Swiftly fly the years
一个季节接着一个季节
One season following another
充满了幸福
Laden with happiness
和泪水
And tears
这就是它们叫粪金龟的原因
So, you see, that's why they call it a dung beetle.
不见得吧
You don't say.
还挺好吃的
And yet still so tasty.
那也是我的最爱
Oh, yeah, and they're my favorite, too.
跟医生讲的一样
Just what the doctor ordered.
无所事事一天后
Yep. After a long day of doing nothing...
休息一下真好
it's good to kick back.
三个朋友一起无忧无虑
Three pals and no worries.
你还能要求什么
What more could you want?
我累了
I'm bushed.
我要去睡觉了
Think l'll turn in for the night.
我要出去
I'm out.
我跟你后面
Right behind you.
你们折磨死我了
You're killing me.
丁满  轮到你说晚安了
Timon, it's your turn to say good night.
晚安
Good night.
好好睡
Sleep tight.
祝今晚梦见臭虫
Dream of bedbugs tonight.
你得承认
You got to admit...
我们在那里过得不错
we had a pretty good thing going there.
我们本来可以一直过下去
We could've gone on like that forever.
只是我们忽略了一个
Except for one teeny weeny little thing...
很小很小的细节
we forgot to count on.
娜娜?
Nala?
-你怎么...  -你怎么...
-How did you... -How did you...
这是个灾难  彭彭...  我告诉你  这是个灾难
This is a disaster, Pumbaa... a disaster, I tell you.
你是说他们好像是
You mean because they've finally found each other...
寻找真爱多年...
like two soul mates joined across the years...
终于再度重逢的情人
by the bonds of true love?
天真无邪的小彭彭
Sweet, innocent little Pumbaa.
她会毁了我们
She's going to put a stake right through the heart...
哈库拉马塔塔的生活方式
of our hakuna matata.
那我们应该要采取行动
Then I guess we ought to do something.
我知道该怎么做
And I know just what it is.
彭彭  今晚无论如何  都不能让他们感觉到爱
Pumbaa, we can't let them feel the love tonight.
你今晚能感受到这份爱吗
Can you feel the love tonight?
真浪漫
That's so romantic.
今晚你能感受到...
Can you feel the love...
今晚你能感受到这份爱吗
Can you feel the love tonight?
安详静谧的夜晚
The peace the evening brings?
这招真灵
Well, that worked like a dream.
真的?
It did?
你听不懂这是一种讽刺吗
Sarcasm is a foreign language to you, isn't it?
你看
Look!
你能否感受到
Can you feel the love...
她在抛媚眼
She's making those eyes.
他对她笑
He's smiling that smile.
他们在笑...
They're laughing...
在拥抱...
and hugging...
在...
and...
如果他今晚坠入爱河
And if he falls in love tonight
那一切就结束了
It can be assumed
他和我们的自由日子
His carefree days
也完蛋了
With us are history
简单说  我们的朋友就报销了
ln short, our pal is doomed
算啦  哥儿们
That's it, buddy.
我们竭尽了全力  但是还是失去了他
We gave it our best shot, but he's a goner.
还不一定
Maybe not.
你从不放弃  对吧
You never give up, do you?
你看
Look.
你甚至不知道我经厉过什么
You don't even know what l've been through.
-如果你告诉我  我就知道了  -算了
- l would if you'd ust tell me. - Forget it.
很好
Fine!
彭彭  你知道这意味着什么?
Pumbaa, do you know what this means?
他没办法表达感情  而她对他还有疑虑?
He can't express his feelings and she has commitment issues?
我们赢了  把他们拆散了
We won. We split them up.
这是件好事吗
And that's a good thing?
看来他受到的打击不小
He seems to be taking it kind of hard.
我知道  可怜的家伙
Yeah, I know. Look, l...
可对我们来说是好事...
But it's the best thing for us.
我是说  对他  我们走吧  彭彭
I mean for him. Let's go, Pumbaa.
我觉得暴风雨要来了
I think this storm's coming to a head.
哈库拉马塔塔安全啦  哥儿们
Hakuna matata is safe at last, pal...
因为不论什么事  都无法带走我们的小家伙
because nothing's going to take our boy away now.
他走了?  你说什么  他走了?
He's gone? What do you mean, he's gone?
就像那只狒狒说的
It's just like the baboon said.
国王已经回来了
The king has returned.
你要我再说一遍吗
You want me to go over it again?
是的  不过请你
Yes, please, but be a dear...
直接跳到辛巴那段...
and just skip to the part about Simba...
我不是嫌你童年不有趣
not that your childhood wasn't fascinating.
好  听着  辛巴才是国王
OK, look, Simba's the rightful king...
可是他失踪以后...
but after he disappeared...
刀疤自封为王
Scar proclaimed himself the king...
和土狼结成了联盟
and formed an alliance with the hyenas.
可怜的辛巴  那个卖国贼  背信忘义
Poor Simba... the treachery, the villainy...
卑鄙下流  真是丢脸
the sheer indescribable horror.
她为什么要逗我们
Blah, blah, blah. Why is she toying with us?
这个母老虎想吃掉我们
This crazy chick is going to eat us.
辛巴一定要回家  向他的叔叔挑战
Simba has to go home to challenge his uncle...
重新夺回属于他的王位
and reclaim his rightful place as king.
你们还不明白吗
Don't you get it?
辛巴需要我们...  就是现在
Simba needs us... now!
他需要我们?
He needs us?
那他就不该离开我们
Then he shouldn't have left us!
如果他要回去  做他的"陛下"
lf he wants to run off to be ''His Highness''...
那我会说
well, I say
"越快走越好"
don't let the branches hit you on the way out.
把哈库拉马塔塔留给真正欣赏它的人
Leave hakuna matata to someone who appreciates it.
可是  丁满  没有辛巴  就不哈库拉马塔塔了
But, Timon, it's not really hakuna matata without Simba.
你怎么啦  不哈库拉马塔塔?
What's gotten into you? Not hakuna matata?
简直是疯话  我告诉你  这是疯话
That's crazy talk... crazy talk, I tell you.
这里一切都没有变...
Nothing's changed here.
辛巴来以前  我们也一样哈库拉马塔塔
We had hakuna matata before Simba...
现在我们依然哈库拉马塔塔
and we've still got it now.
丁满  我们该去帮助  我们的朋友
We got to go help our friend, Timon.
彭彭  你也是?
Et tu, Pumbaa?
你打算就这样离开  放弃这一切?
You're just going to walk away, give up on all this?
还说什么朋友要永远在一起
What happened to ''friends stick together to the end''?
我正打算问你相同的问题呢
I was about to ask you the same thing.
我所需要的一切都在这里了
I got everything I ever wanted right here.
这还比较像样点
Now, this is more like it...
多的是空间
elbow room.
天哪...
Oh, boy, oh, boy, oh, boy.
哈库拉马塔塔
Hakuna Matata
多么美妙的词语
What a wonderful phrase
哈库拉马塔塔
Hakuna Matata
不是一时流行的词语
Ain't no passing craze
意思是...
It means...
无忧无虑
No worries.
是你  不要  什么也别说
You. No, no. Don't say a word.
我知道你要说什么
I know what you're going to say.
你找到哈库拉马塔塔了吗
Did you find hakuna matata?
是的  我找到了
Well, yes, I did.
谢谢你
Thank you very much.
我很幸福
And I am happy.
非常幸福
Happy, happy, deliriously happy.
我懂了  幸福  是吗
I see. Happy, is it?
如果你真的幸福  为什么看起来很痛苦
So, if you're so happy, why do you look so miserable?
你说我痛苦?
Miserable, you say?
我为什么要痛苦
Why should I be miserable?
我不知道  也许是
Oh, I don't know. Maybe my two best pals...
我两个最好的朋友抛弃了我
in the world deserted me.
他们要去做英雄
Heh. They've headed off on some heroic mission.
我的朋友都走了
My friends are gone.
我的哈库拉马塔塔也跟他们一起走了
And my hakuna matata went with them.
拜托一下
Would you mind?
谢谢  我很高兴我们聊开了
Thanks. l'm glad we had this talk.
我在这里的工作结束了
My work here is done.
朋友要永远在一起
Friends stick together to the end.
你怎么那样跑啊  那样也算是跑吗
What was with the running? lf you can call that running.
我这是为了让你能赶上
I was giving you time to catch up.
你这个大笨蛋
Aw, you big lug.
上来吧  朋友
Hop on, buddy.
我们有场仗在等着打呢
We got a fight to catch.
我们冲过草原吧
Let's whip some grass.
这里就是传奇的所在  有壮烈的战斗
This is the stuff of legends... an epic struggle...
也是英雄诞生之地
the place where heroes are born.
彭彭  这可能  是我们最难忘的时刻了
Pumbaa, this could be our finest hour.
烤野猪
Luau!
想吃美味多汁的猪肉吗
lf you're hungry for a hunk of fat and uicy meat
吃我朋友彭彭  因为他...
Eat my buddy Pumbaa here because he...
我们直接开始追逐吧
Let's just cut to the chase, shall we?
好啊
Oh, sure.
搞什么...
What the...
我最爱彭彭早上的味道了
I love the smell of Pumbaa in the morning.
猪头  移开你的屁股
Hey, move your tush, honey.
妈妈?  麦斯叔叔?
Ma? Uncle Max?
-啊  丁满  -丁满?
- Oh, Timmy! - Timon?
你们在这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
找你啊  妈咪来了
Looking for you. Aw. Mommy's here.
让我来介绍一下  我最好的朋友
Well, let me introduce you to my best friend.
彭彭  我妈妈  麦斯叔叔
Pumbaa, Ma, Uncle Max.
妈妈  麦斯叔叔  彭彭
Ma, Uncle Max, Pumbaa.
瞧  是辛巴  那一定是他的叔叔刀疤了
Look, there's Simba, and that must be his uncle Scar.
太好了  他们谈和了
Oh, good, they're talking things out...
事情就该这样
which is how it should be.
我觉得
You know, I have a feeling...
一切都会没事的
everything's going to be just fine.
但是话说回来...
On the other hand...
土狼在上面保护刀疤
the hyenas are up there protecting Scar.
我们该怎么办呢
What do we do?
嗯  我有个计划
Well, l've got a plan.
我们能帮什么
How can we help?
妈妈  麦斯叔叔  你们挖个陷阱
Ma, Uncle Max, you're going to dig a trap.
我们需要...
We're going to need...
这么说吧
dare I say it?
地道  很多很多的地道
Tunnels... lots and lots of tunnels.
彭彭  你和我
And, Pumbaa, you and me...
我们一定要把土狼从辛巴那里引走
we've got to get those hyenas away from Simba.
把他们引入陷阱?
And lure them into the trap?
什么都瞒不过你
Nothing gets past you.
彭彭  来  我们上吧
Come on, Pumbaa, Let's ride.
丁满和往常有点不一样
Something's different about Timon.
你也觉得?  他穿了条裙子
You think? He's wearing a dress!
嗨  彭彭
Hey, Pumbaa.
一个只有有半个脑袋的土狼  叫什么?
What do you call a hyena with half a brain?
不知道  丁满  叫什么
Beats me, Timon. What?
土蛋
Gifted.
他们在说我们
They're talking about us.
你们死前  绝对会后悔讲这些话
For your last meal, you're going to eat those words.
妈妈  我想我们已经引起他们的注意了
Ma, I think we got their attention.
还没有  继续拖住他们
Not yet. Keep stalling.
好吧
OK.
不会吧
You got to be kidding me.
好了吗  妈妈?
Now, Ma?
还需要点时间  宝贝
Need more time, honey.
自由式
Freestyle.
再来  再来
Encore, encore.
不  你是说"开胃菜"
No, no, no. You mean entree, entree.
对  直接把他们吃掉
No, you right. Let's just eat them.
好了吗  妈妈?
ls it ready yet, Ma?
还没有  继续拖延
Not yet. Keep stalling.
等等  等一下
Wait, wait, wait, wait. Hold on a second.
丁满  你在干什么
Timon? What are you doing?
非洲大草原肉食动物之土狼  桑琪
Shenzi Marie Predatora Veldetta Jacquelina Hyena...
我是否有荣幸娶你  做我的新娘?
would you do me the honor of becoming my bride?
我想没有
I don't think so.
桑琪  拜托  我知道你的想法
Shenzi Marie, please. I know what you're thinking.
我们差异太大  不可能
We're too different. It'll never work.
想想孩子会长成什么样
What will the children look like?
这会打破很多  自然法则
That violates so many laws of nature.
听我说  像我们这种
Listen to me. The problems of a couple of wacky kids...
配对生下来的不正常孩子
like us don't amount to a hill of termites...
在这个疯狂的世界里  根本不是什么问题
in this nutty circle of life thing.
所以我问你  现在不结几时结?
And so I ask you... if not now, when?
你如果不要我  要谁?
lf not me, who?
我好孤独
I'm lonely.
我能做你的伴郎吗
Can I be your best man?
我说  我们跳过婚礼  直接吃喜酒吧
I say we skip the wedding and go straight to the buffet.
现在?
Now?
当然啦  你准备好了吗
Sure, if you're ready.
现在  麦斯  现在
Now, Max, now!
土狼进洞啦
Hyenas in the hole!
快来帮我  我弄不成
I need help. It didn't work.
我这里行了
Hey, it works for me.
我们该怎么办
What are we going to do?
什么
What?
丁满  不
Timon, no!
我们吃了他们吧
Let's get 'em.
依我看刀疤完了
I'd say Scar is down and out.
我们赢了
We did it! We did it!
丁满在哪里  我的宝贝呢
Where's Timon? Where's my baby?
他受伤了  啊  不  他死了  或者更糟
He's hurt! Oh, no! He's dead! Or worse!
我们得找到他
We got to find him. We've got to find him.
没事  妈妈
It's OK, Ma.
不要说没事
Oh, please. lt is not OK!
别跟我说没事
Don't you tell me it's OK!
丁满
Timmy!
我的儿子...
My son...
是英雄
the hero.
你漏了一处
You missed a spot.
真棒啊
That's so beautiful.
憋死啦  不能呼吸啦
Choking. Not breathing.
没有你们我是无法成功的
I couldn't have done it without you guys.
我们的好小子
That's our boy.
我发过誓绝对不哭的
I promised myself I wasn't going to cry.
丁满  你真的长大了很多
You've really come a long way, Timon.
你找到你要找的地方了吗
Did you find what you were looking for?
我找到了一个梦寐以求的地方
I found a place that was beyond my wildest dreams...
可是那里还不算是家
but it still wasn't home.
妈妈  我们回家吧
Let's go home, Ma.
欢迎回到我们的新家
Welcome to our new home...
这里没有会吃我们的野兽
a predator-free environment.
丁满  我真的要称赞你  这里什么都有
I got to hand it to you, Timon. This place has everything.
现在我们团聚了  这才算家
Well, now that we're all here, it does.
鹤...
Crane...
展开翅膀  然后优雅的转身
spreads its wings, turns with dainty hands.
挖个地道  挖呀挖  挖个地道  挖呀挖
Digga tunnah, dig, digga tunnah
我们再也不用挖地洞了
We're never gonna dig another tunnah
挖个地道  挖呀挖  挖个地道  挖呀挖
Digga tunnah, dig, digga tunnah
土狼啊  来不了啦
Nevermore the hyena come
歌颂伟大的丁满
Sing the praises of brave Timon
最勇敢的狐獴
The bravest meerkat we've ever known
从没想到  他会帮助辛巴获胜
Never dreamed he'd help Simba shine
事实证明和猪交朋友是很酷的
Proved it's cool to hang out with swine
意外的救星
Accidentally saved the day
照计行事
Planned it so it would look that way
把我们从沙土中解放出来
Brought us out of the dirt and sand
把他的家人带到了幸福之地
Led his family to the promised land
歌颂伟大的丁满
Sing the praises of brave Timon
最勇敢的狐獴
Bravest meerkat we've ever known
就这样...
Well, that's it...
大结局  幸福的结局
the big wrap-up, the happy ending...
风光的收场
the grand finale.
已经结束了?
It's over already?
结局就是这样
Well, Pumbaa, that's the thing about endings.
最后...  就是结局
They come at the end.
再看一次好吗
Can we watch it again?
彭彭  我们才刚看过  明天再看吧
Pumbaa, we ust saw it. Maybe tomorrow.
你们在干什么
Hey, what are you guys doing?
你没有告诉我们  你们要看电影
You didn't tell me you were watching the movie.
我也要看
I want to watch, too.
妈妈  我们刚看完  结束了
Ma, we just finished. Show's over.
那你要倒一下带子
Well, you're just going to have to rewind it.
妈妈
Ma!
麦斯叔叔  我们要看那部电影
Uncle Max, we're going to watch the movie.
哦  不
Oh, no!
我带来了很多爆米花
Hey, I brought extra butter.
你们还要再看一遍?
Hey, you guys are watching the movie?
凡是值得看的故事  就值得多看几遍
Any story worth telling is worth telling twice.
-怎么...  -啊  对不起
- What the... - Excuse me.
-对不起  -对不起
- Excuse me. - Excuse me.
-对不起  -闪一边去
- Excuse me. - Get out of the way.
这群人是谁
Who is this crowd?
前面的  坐下
Hey, down in front!
哎哟
Gawrsh!
你好
Aloha!
小心点
Watch it!
好啦  朋友  你赢了
OK, buddy, you win.
你不介意吗
Sure you don't mind?
哈库拉马塔塔
Hakuna Matata
嘘...
Sorry.
丁满...
Timon...
我还是不习惯太多人
I still don't do so well in crowds.